嘿，你们好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, and welcome back to my game engine series
所以上次我们讨论了层，创建了LayerStack系统，如果你们还没有看过的话，一定要看一看
so last time we talked about layers, and we made the LayerStack system, make sure you check that out, if you haven't already
并且现在我们已经了解了所有这些，我想继续朝着我现在想要的方向前进
and now that we've got all of that, what I would like to kind of proceed with in the direction that I want to take this right now
接下来的步骤实际上就是让ImGui跑起来，如果你们还不知道的话，ImGui就像
and the next steps is actually getting ImGUI running, if that's what you guys don't know, ImGui is like a
它是一种即时模式的GUI系统
it's an immediate mode kind of GUI system
所以如果你们还没有在我的OpenGL系列看过ImGui的视频，一定要去看看哦
so if you haven't checked out my OpenGL series video on ImGui, definitely check that out
链接就放在那儿的，它让我们可以很容易引入的即时模式ImGui
it'll be linked up there as well, it just lets us kind of really easily kind of immediate mode ImGui
只是为了让我们比如调试东西或点击按钮，让事情发生，它是一个UI，对吧
just so that we can like debug things or click on buttons and have things happened, it's a UI, right
那就是它允许我们做的，而且很容易使用
that's what it lets us do, and it's really easy to use
对于我来说，那是我喜欢在游戏引擎中设置的第一个东西
for me, that's one of the first things that I love setting up in a game engine
或者任何一种真正像任何一种图形项目
or any kind of really like any kind of graphics project
真的是因为既能看到信息，又能调整值，或者能让事情发生
really because being able to kind of both see information, as well as kind of adjust values, or kind of make things happen
那就好像没有它我就活不下去，好像我不认为这是可能的，好像我不需要它
that's like I couldn't live without that, like I don't think that's possible, like I don't want it
例如，每次重新编译代码时，我想更改一个变量，对吧，我只想在屏幕上有一个小滑块
for example recompiled code every time, I want to change a variable, right, I just want to have a little slider on the screen
那类东西对我可能知道的OpenGL系列视频非常有用
that kind of stuff, it's really useful for that, and definitely that, that OpenGL series video that I may know
ImGui有点让你们熟悉
ImGui kind of familiarize you guys with that
如果你们还没有听说过，或者你们无法想象为什么这样的东西可能真的有用
if you haven't heard of it yet, or if you can't kind of imagine why something like that might actually be useful
好吧，无论如何，为了让ImGui真正跑起来，我们需要做什么，或者我们不需要这样做
alright, anyway, so in order to get ImGui actually working though, what we need to do, well we don't need to do this
但我们首先要实现这个，因为这或多或少会证明我会如何实现
but we're going to do this first, because it's going to be more or less future proof how I'm going implementation
我们需要一种实际使用现代OpenGL的方法，所以现在我们使用的图形接口是OpenGL
we need a way to actually use modern OpenGL, so right now the graphics api that we're kind of going with is OpenGL
Hazel将是一种，Hazel的体系架构肯定会支持任何类型的图形接口，对吧
Hazel will be kind of, the architecture of Hazel will for sure support any kind of graphics api, right
现在只是从OpenGL开始，这儿有很多原因
right now it's just gonna be OpenGL to begin with, there's a lot of reasons for that
我想我在计划视频中谈到了那一点，嗯，别担心，不会的，不会的
I think I covered that in the planning video, um and don't worry like it's not gonna be, it's not gonna be really
这对我们来说一点都不难，就像切换到Vulcan或者你们知道的添加到DirectX一样
it's not gonna be hard at all for us, like switch to Vulcan or like you know add on DirectX
那应该很容易，可能需要一天的工作
that should be really quite easy, probably like a days worth of work
嗯，但在一开始，我们将使用OpenGL，因为它是最简单的接口
um but in the beginning, we're gonna go with OpenGL, just because it is both the simplest api that is out there
而且它也是目前我们实际拥有的跨平台的接口，那也是简单的级别，对吧
and also it's kind of, it's the most cross platform api that we actually have at the moment, that is also the level of simplicity, right
所以关于DirectX11，你们可能会争辩说也没那么难
so DirectX11 and you could argue is not that difficult as well
而对于新手来说，或多或少是在DirectX12级别上
whereas welcome is more or less on DirectX12 level
它可是处于更底层的接口，但是DirectX11这种仅在Windows上可用
which is a lot more lower level, however DirectX11 are only available on Windows
我希望人们能够轻松地将其移植到其他平台，尤其是，因为我们有premake设置
and I want people to easily be able to port this to other platforms especially, because we have premake setup
它应该可以正常运行，不管怎样，我认为我们正在使用的任何特定于Windows的代码
it should just work pretty much right, I think we're using any windows specific code anyway
好吧，我不想为这一期辩护
alright, I don't want to defend this episode talking about what we're doing
基本上我们需要做的是，需要一种将所有现代OpenGL函数从GPU加载到C++中的方法，对吧
basically what we need to do is we need a way to load all of the modern OpenGL functions from our GPU drivers into just our C++ code, right
所以我希望能够调用存储在图形驱动程序中的函数，那基本上就是我的想法
so I want to be able to call functions that are stored inside our graphics drivers, that's basically the idea
现在在OpenGL系列中，我们使用了一种叫做GLEW的东西，就是OpenGL扩展包装器
now in the OpenGL series, we did, we use something called GLEW, GLEW,  which is the OpenGL, like extension wrangler or something
如果你们想看看那个版本，左上角还有一个指向那个视频的链接
there's a link in the top left corner as well to that video, in case you want to check out that version
在这个系列中，对于这个引擎，我实际上要使用一些不同的东西
this in this series, for this engine, I'm actually going to use something different
实际上我要用一个叫做GLAD的库，我不知道，它是否代表什么
I'm actually going to use something called GLAD, which is, I don't know, if it stands for something
可能是的，它只是说基于官方规范的多语言gl加载生成器
it probably does, it just says multi language gl loaded generator based on the official specs
无论如何，根据我的经验，它比GLEW好一点，更现代一点
anyway, it's a little bit better and more modern in my experience than GLEW
GLEW是我过去经常使用的库，但这个更容易配置
GLEW something that I used to use kind of in the past, but this is a little bit more configurable
只是有一点，我只是更喜欢这个，但我只是想让你们知道那个
and it's just a little bit, I just like it a little bit more, but but I just want you to know that
这里有一个真正的区别，比如，OepnGL系列只是我们使用GLEW构建的一种小框架的教程
there's a real difference, like for example, the OpenGL series is kind of the little framework, where we have there is built using GLEW
虽然这儿我用GLAD，但它们都做同样的事情，我不认为，它不是空的
whereas I'm using GLAD to this, they do the same thing, I don't think, it's not empty
你们会注意到任何性能上的差异或类似的东西，我只想在这里使用GLAD
you'll notice any performance differences or anything like that, I'm just gonna use GLAD here
因为它有点现代，但除此之外，基本上这两个东西的功能就是
because it's a little bit more modern, but apart from that, basically the function of both these things is to
检查我们的图形驱动程序dll，然后加载我们知道的某些函数
check out our kind of graphics driver dll, and just load certain functions that we know are in there
因此，我们可以从C++代码中调用它们，那就是这些库所做的，让我们看看如何设置它
so that we can then call them from our C++ code, that is what these libraries do, let's take a look at how we can set this up
它应该非常简单，我们将首先使用网站进行配置，然后下载它
it should be dead simple, we're going to actually configure it using the website first, then download it
然后将其作为一个独立项目添加，然后再添加一个premake文件，使其成为一个单独的项目
then add it as a separate project, and then add a premake file to it, so that it is a separate project
我们只是将其作为存储库的一部分提交
and we're just going to commit it as part of our repository
所以它不会像我在GLEW中所做的那样，像来自另一个存储库的拷贝
so it's not going to be like a fork from another repository like I did with GLEW
就像我也要用ImGui一样，好吧，让我们开始吧
and like I'm going to do with ImGui as well, alright, let's just jump into it
好了，那么就是我们这里的这个网站，我会把链接在下面的描述中
okay, so this website that we have here, I'm going to link in the description below
但基本上，让我们配置一下我们真正想要的GLAD文件的样子
but basically just let's kind of configure what we actually want the GLAD file to look like
所以这实际上会为我们生成一些代码，所以语言当然是C/C++
so this will actually generate some code for us essentially, so the language of course will be C/C++
OpenGL将成为我们的规范，我们将使用核心，完成核心配置文件
OpenGL is going to be our specification, we're going to go with the core, complete with the core profile
因为我们不需要任何类型的兼容性函数，这意味着我们不希望它支持不推荐使用的函数
because we don't want any kind of compatibility functions, which means we don't want it to support deprecated functions
对于gl扩展，我将使用core 4.6的接口，对吧
the api I'm gonna go with core 4.6, right, for gl extensions
我现在真的不想说那些，我很难说，我想要某些扩展
I don't really right now is very difficult to me to say that, I want certain extensions
因为当我们开始优化事情，或者我们想做一些新奇的事情时，这很可能会有帮助
because this will most likely lend itself, when we get to optimizing things, or we want to do some fancy things
就像我不知道一样，就像在DirectX和OpenGL之间共享内存一样，可能是那样的东西
like I don't know, just like sharing memory between DirectX and OpenGL, potentially stuff like that
大多数扩展都不应该是，我认为我们现在不需要任何扩展
most of these extensions should not be, I don't think we'll need any of them right now
所以很明显，一旦我们做了它们需要的事情，我们就可以重新生成这个文件
so and obviously, once we're doing they need them, we can just regenerate this file
所以那就是我现在使用的设置，当然是4.6 gl，然后是核心配置文件
so that's kind of the settings that I'm using right now 4.6 gl of course, and then the core profile
那么现在我要做的就是生成一个加载器，我只需点击generate
so now all I have to do is we'll generate a loader, I'll just hit generate
然后在这里创建这样的网页，我只需点击glad.zip，下载它
and then this will create this kind of web page here, I'm going to just click on glad.zip to download it
然后，那应该是我们需要的一切，所以如果我打开它，我们已经包含在src中了
and then that should pretty much have everything we need, so if I open that, we have included in src
好了，那么我要把它复制到Hazel里面，我要转到我们的解决方案目录
okay, so I'm gonna copy that inside Hazel, I'm gonna go to our solution directory here
我将进入Hazel，我将进入vendor，我将创建一个名为GLAD的新文件夹
I'm going to go into Hazel, I'm going to go into vendor, I'm going to make a new folder called GLAD
我想把它粘贴到那里，你们可以看到，我的意思是，有一个源文件，它相当大
I want to paste that in there, and you can see that, I mean, there's one source file, it's quite large
还有一堆包含文件，我们可能根本不需要KHR
and then there's also like a bunch of include files, we probably won't need KHR are at all
GLAD的版本是我们所看到的，然后就是那样，对吧
Glad age is kind of what we're looking at, and then that's kind of kind of it, right
所以我们现在需要做的就是创建一个premake文件
so all we need to do now is make a premake file
然后把这个premake文件添加到我们的premake文件中
and then add kind of this premake file into our premake file
所以如果我打开这个premake文件，打开premake文件大约5次4秒
so if I open up this premake file, upset premake file about five times and 4 seconds
但无论如何，你们可以看到，我们包含了
but anyway, you can see that we include
你们知道的，也就是这个，我们也将基本上包含了GLAD
you know this one, we also are going to essentially be including GLAD
对吧，然后这些包含目录也一样，我要复制，所以我们在这里也有了GLAD
right, and then these include directories as well, I'm going to duplicate, so that we have GLAD here
然后你们知道，当我们在这里包含某些东西时，希望你们喜欢这个直播撸码的事业
and then you know, when we come down here to include certain things, hopefully you guys are enjoying this live coding cause
我不知道，很多人都在抱怨这一点，我会尽可能多地进行直播撸码
I don't know, a lot of people looking complaining about that, I'll try and do live coding as much as I can
但有时它只是变得有点困难，GLAD的链接也好了
but sometimes it just gets a little bit difficult, well linked GLAD as well
一个好方法就是搜索GLFW所在的任何地方
a good idea is just a search kind of for wherever GLFW is
然后看看我们是否需要做这件困难的事，那就是我现在的策略
and then just maybe see if we need to do this difficult, and that's going to be my pro strat right now
是的，看起来不错，好吧
yeah that looks pretty good, okay
所以我的意思是，最重要的就是我们需要把它作为一个项目联系起来
so I mean the biggest thing is we need to link it as a project
因为它当然要编译成一个静态库，然后我们还需要
because of course it's going to compile into a static library, and then also we need to
确保包含目录实际上是你们现在包含Hazel的目录
make sure that the include directories are actually you now include directories for Hazel
差不多了，好了，完成了，实际上现在我们需要为GLAD创建一个premake
that's pretty much it, okay, so that's done, now we need to actually make a premake file for GLAD
所以我要做的是，如果进入GLFW，就可以拷贝这个premake文件，把它放在这里
so what I'll do is, if I go into GLFW, I can just kind of steal that premake file, put it in here
然后我们可以看看它是什么样子的，所以项目名称应该是GLAD
and then we can take a look at what it looks like, so project name would be GLAD
这实际上是一个，GLAD作为一个C项目，用C写的GLAD
this is actually a I'm actually GLAD as a C project as well isn't it one language is GLAD written and it is C
好了，很好，所以这将非常相似，它将是一个静态库，项目名称就是GLAD
okay, great, so this is going to be quite similar, it's going to be a static library, project name is GLAD
输出目录与现在包含的文件一样的，我们有GLAD/glad.h，所以包含GLAD
output directory is the same right now files in include, we have GLAD/glad.h, so include GLAD
这个只是小写的，也就是glad/glad.h，这里的文件非常明确，还有KHR/khrplatform.h
it's just low case glad/glad.h, whoops, I want to actually be quite explicit with the files here, khr include KHR/khrplatform.h
我的意思是，我很明显可以让它包含所有我们用Hazel做的东西
I mean, I could just obviously have it include everything kind of like what we have with Hazel
但我确实想在这里明确一点，只是为了让大家更清楚glad.c
but I do want to actually be explicit here, just so that a little bit more aware glad.c
因为我们应该只有三个文件，不管怎样，好了，那就是，那就是GLAD的三个文件
because we should only have three files, anyway, okay, so those are, those are the three files the GLAD kind of has
我不认为这里有太多错误。不，看起来不错，这些东西，老实说，我真的不想要这些
I don't think of many mistakes here no that looks good, this stuff, I don't really want any of this, to be honest
所以我不认为我们需要任何真正的miss deck runtime之类的东西
so kind of I don't think we need any of this really miss deck runtime and stuff
我们需要，我不会做多线程，好吧，我会处理掉这个，这显然是最新的
we will need, I'm not gonna do multi threaded, okay, I'll kind of get rid of this, and this should obviously be latest
我可能也应该GLFW改成那样，根本没有构建选项
I probably should have to edit the GLFW to be that as well, no build options at all
最后我要做的是把这个包含目录添加到includedirs
and the last thing I want to do is actually add this include directory to the includedirs
我们这里有，所以就是include，好了，那是我想做的一件事
that we have here, so include, alright, and that is it one thing I want to do actually
因为我刚看了一下这个网站，意识到Glad并不都是大写的
because I've kind of just looked at this website, and realized that Glad really isn't all in upper cases
也许我真的想让它变成小写的
maybe I do actually want to make it more kind of lower case
如果我们回到我们的另一份premake文件，我可能把这个GLAD改成像那样的(Glad)
so if we go back to our other premake file, I'll just maybe make this GLAD like that
并且可能还会更改文件夹名称，因为我认为它显然不代表任何东西
and probably change the folder name as well, because I don't think it stands for anything apparently
或者至少网站暗示了那一点，但事实并非如此，所以我们会确保任何地方都会是Glad
or at least the website implies that, it doesn't, so we'll kind of make sure that any places is Glad
这才是正确的写法，很好，如果我们转到目录，我不确定这是否会添加我们重命名
it's in the correct way, good, and then if we go to disc, I'm not sure if this will add us rename
好了，它做得很好，只是因为在Windows中，目录名和文件名不区分大小写
okay, it did good, just because in Windows of course directory names and file names are not case sensitive
好了，好了，那么一切都准备好了，应该可以了
okay, cool, so there we go we've got everything here, this should just work
我们现在所能做的就是尝试和更新我们的产品，希望一切都能正常运行
what we can do now is just try and regenerate our products, and hopefully everything will just work
所以没有从premake得到任何错误，如果重新加载它，会得到那个Glad，好吧，太棒了
so we didn't get any error from premake, and if we reload it, we should get Glad here, okay, fantastic
然后除了这里有我们所有的文件，这是完美的
and then apart from having all of our files here, which is perfect
我们还应该看到Hazel现在引用到了Glad，就是那样的
we should also see that Hazel now references Glad, which it does
所以你们可以看到，这是我根据记忆制作的一个premake脚本
so you can see, that was me kind of making a premake script pretty much from memory
我复制并粘贴了GLFW的，但你们可以看到premake是多么简单，我喜欢premakes
and I did copy and paste the GLFW one, but you can see just how simple premake is, I love premakes
好了，让我们构建整个解决方案，看看会发生什么
okay, let's build our whole solution and see what happens
但，好了，成功了，太棒了，那么一切都可以了
and but, okay, one succeeded, fantastic, so everything's succeeded
所以现在我们真正需要做的就是初始化它，对吧
so now all we really need to do to use Glad is initialize it, right
所以这里有一个函数，可以让我们实际加载一些东西
so there is a function inside here, that lets us actually load something
好吧，那不是，我想是glLoad或其他什么，glLoad glLoader在那里
okay, that's not, I think it's glad  glLoad or something, glad load glLoader there it is
好了，那么如果我们指定这个，我希望这个没有，我想我不记得这些东西的文档在哪里了
okay, so this if we specify this, and I wish that this had not even, I don't think I remember where the documentation is for this stuff
看看Github，也许我们会看到如何使用它
look at Github, maybe we'll see how to use it
无论如何，我知道如何使用它，因为我以前使用过它
anyway, I know how to use it, because I've used it before
但本质上我们需要做的就是调用这个函数，使用我们拥有的加载类函数
but essentially what we need to do is just call this function, with the load kind of function that we have
那将允许我们从那里加载dll文件或函数，所以要做到这一点，我将进入WindowsWindow
that will allow us to load kind of dll files or functions from there, so to do that, I'm just going to go into WindowsWindow
然后在这儿，我们初始化GLFW，并创建OpenGL上下文
and then over here is where we kind of initialize GLFW, and also create the OpenGL context
所以，一旦我们有了那个上下文，那就是我想实际使用Glad的地方
so once we've kind of made that context, that's where I kind of want to actually do the Glad stuff
所以我们将调用gladLoadGLLoader
so we'll do gladLoadGLLoader
首先，让我快速地包含Glad，所以它在包含部分
and let me just quickly include Glad, first of all, so it's in the include part
所以我们只能看到glad/glad.h，就像那样，这里应该是小写的
so we should just be able to see glad/glad.h like that, this can be lower case
然后gloadLoadGLLoader当然需要一个GLADloadproc
and then gloadLoadGLLoader of course needs a GLADloadproc
然后我们要给它的函数实际上是glfw
and then the function that we're going to give it is actually glfw
实际上就是glfwGetProcAddress，好了
it's actually glfwGetProcAddress like that, okay
然后我们要做的就是，在这里对status做一个CORE_ASSERT
and then all we'll do is, we'll do a CORE_ASSERT here on status
然后你们知道的，不能初始化Glad之类的，好了，酷
and then you know fail to initialize Glad or something like that initialize, okay, cool
所以那应该是我们需要做的全部，我们要在这里打一个断点，然后按f5来运行这个代码
so that should be pretty much all that we need to do, we're gonna put a break point here, and then hit f5 to run this code
错误OpenGL标头已包含，好的，很酷，所以移除这个包含Glad已经提供了它
error OpenGL header already included, okay, cool, so remove this include Glad already provides it
所以我们两次包含OpenGL很不爽，让我们看看到底发生了什么
so it's unhappy that we're including OpenGL twice, let's see what this is actually happening
所以这里包含了GLFW，我不知道为什么我们要这么做，因为我认为我们不需要它
so here GLFW is included, I don't know why we did that, because I didn't think we need any of it
我想做的可能是最终做这样的事情，所以我们将在这里定义struct GLFWWindow，一起
what I want to do is probably end up doing something like this, so we'll do struct GLFWWindow here, just together that
然后在Glad之后包含GLFW，它不会，可能有一种方法就是不包含gl.h
and then include GLFW after Glad, it doesn't, there's probably a way to just not have it include gl.h
因为，是的，我相信你们也能说出来，因为这儿就有GLFW_INCLUDE_NONE
and because, yeah I'm sure you can tell it not too, because there's GLFW_INCLUDE_NONE
所以我想也许我们应该这样做，所以在Hazel里面，是的，就是那个premake
so I think that maybe we should just do that, so inside Hazel, and that's right, when it is and premake don't we
我们将回到Hazel，我们将回到premake，然后我们将在这里使用其中一个定义
so we'll go back to Hazel, we'll go back to premake, and then one of the defines that we will use somewhere here
我们对系统Windows的定义在哪里，所以我不知道，如果我只想对Windows这样做
where are our defines for system Windows, so I don't know, if I want to do this just for Windows
我现在在WindowsWindow，是的，我们把它放在这里，就是GLFW_INCLUDE_NONE
my minutes in the WindowsWindow for now, yeah let's just put it here, we'll do a GLFW_INCLUDE_NONE
好了，那将不包含任何GLFW，它将不包含任何OpenGL头文件
okay, and that just will not include any GLFW, it will not include any OpenGL headers
当你们包含GLFW，那就是想法，所以现在如果我们撤销这个，我们这儿就有了Glad
when you include GLFW, that's the idea, so now if we undo this, and we have Glad here
我的意思是，尝试并构建这个，它应该可以运行，不，它不运行，好了，OpenGL头
what I mean this, try and build this, it should work, no, it's not working, okay, OpenGL header, oh
当然我没有重新生成项目，所以让我们生成项目，重新加载这个，尝试编译那个
well of course I didn't regenerate the projects, so let's generate the projects, reload this, try and compile that
好了，成功了，太棒了，现在我们有了断点，让我们点击f5
and there you go, okay, succeeded fantastic, so now with our break point in place, let's hit f5
好吧，它对这些明确的调用不满意，因为我们需要包含这个glad/glad.h
okay, it's not happy with these clear calls, because we're including this glad/glad.h
因为Glad现在已经了解了OpenGL定义的所有内容，所以看看是否还有其他错误，f5
because glad now has all about OpenGL defines, let's see if we get any other errors nope five
这儿有个短点，status是1，好了，这显然意味着它成功了
there is a break point, and status is one, okay, which obviously means, it succeeded
因为我们设置的是如果它不是零，我们设置的是它不是零
because we're setting if it's not zero, we're setting that it's not zero
好了，太棒了，所以我们基本上可以看到，就那样，一切都完成了，换另一种快速检查下
okay, fantastic, so we can basically see that, that's it, it's all done, another way to quickly check
可能有点像hockey，但如果我们尝试的话，我认为Window::Create()可以创建一切，对吧
which is maybe a little bit hockey, but if we try, I think Window::Create should create everything, right
所以如果我们尝试调用glGenVertexArrays，很明显是有意义的，这里是unsigned
so if we try and do something like glGenVertexArray is clearly something, that is clearly something, that is unsigned something
那就是现代OpenGL，就这样，这个函数不应该为null，对吧
that is modern OpenGL, then that's all, this function should not be null, right
是的，它执行了，它给了我们一个有效的id，所以你们可以看到一切都成功了
so yeah it executed, and it gave us a valid id, so you can see that everything worked successfully
好了，所以那就是我们的设置Glad方式，我不是不认为，我需要和你们一起看看变更
alright, so that is how we set up glad, I'm not don't think, I need to go over the changes with you guys
这将被推送到Github上，你们可以像自己一样看看那些变更，但是是的，所以那就是Glad
this will be pushed to Github, you can look at the changes like yourselves, but yeah so that is Glad
然后在下一期中，我们将能够使用Glad实现ImGui，也就是使用现代OpenGL
and then in the next episode, we'll be able to use Glad to actually implement ImGui using modern OpenGL
好了，所以你们喜欢这期视频吗，如果喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
alright, so have you guys enjoyed this video, if you did, you can hit the like button
同时，非常感谢所有支持这一系列节目的赞助人
also huge thank you to all the patron supporters that made this series possible
如果你们还没在patreon上支持这个系列的话，一定要去看看
if you're not supporting the serie on patreon, definitely go check that out
非常感谢你们，像往常一样，你们会提前一周收到所有的视频
huge thank you to you guys, as always you'll get all the episodes a week early
以及访问我的私有开发分支，我已经在那里做了很多这方面的工作
as well as access to my kind of private development branch in which I've already done a lot of this work
所以你们可以看到未来的几个月，关于这个引擎的发展方向，你们就可以
so you can kind of see months and months ahead, as to where this engine is going, and you can kind of
我的意思是，我在做这件事的时候，我也会
I mean, I kind of as when I work on that I also kind of
你们知道，边提交边做，这样你们就能看到最小的变化
you know, commit as I go, so you can see minimal changes
你们不需要这样，好吧，现在我有了这个完整的引擎，我不知道它是怎么运行的
you don't need to be like, okay, now I've got this complete engine, and I don't know how it works
所以你们可以回顾之前的一些提交，看看它是如何发展的
so you can kind of go back a few commits, and just see how it evolves as well
因为这种dev分支在很大程度上是本系列的发展方向
because that kind of development branch is largely, where this series is going
我确实做了一些改变，比如这里和那里，但大多数情况下都是一样的
I do make changes, like here and there, but mostly it's the same
如果你们有兴趣的话，一定要看看，好了，所以那就是Glad
so if you're interested to, definitely check that out, okay, so that's Glad
这很简单，很容易设置，premake让这很容易，你们也可以看到，所以我很喜欢
it's pretty straightforward, it's pretty easy to set up, premake makes this so fairly easy, as you can see as well, so I love that
在下一期中，我们将了解ImGui的基本实现
in the next episode, we're gonna take a look at basically having a very basic implementation of ImGui
现在我们要添加ImGui子模块
now the thing is we're gonna add ImGui submodule
很明显，我们要做所有这些事情，实际上我们要以他们的OpenGL实现为例
and obviously do all of that stuff, and we're actually gonna take their example OpenGL implementation
从这里开始，如果我要引用他们的示例GLFW实现，我可能不会
and go from there, and probably there, I'm not gonna, if I'm gonna reference their example GLFW implementation
但我不会一字不差地说，因为我想实际制作一个ImGui层，它包含所有那些东西
but I'm not going to just take it word for word, because I want to actually make an ImGui layer, which has all of that stuff
基本上是因为我们真的不需要，你们知道，实现所有的GLFW初始化
basically because we don't really need to, you know, do all of the GLFW initialization
那应该在窗口中显示出来，所以我们将在下一期的ImGui中进行Hack
that should be uptracted in the window, so we're going to kind of hack in ImGui next episode
因为对于我们来说，现在就能够正确地进行渲染还为时过早，原因是我们目前没有渲染器
because it's way too early for us to be able to do it properly, the reason is we don't have a renderer at the moment
好了，显然我们需要能够编译着色器，对吧，所以嗯，但我需要把ImGui配置好，跑起来
okay, and obviously we need to be able to do things like compile shaders, right, so mmm, but I want to get ImGui up and running
因为我们可以很容易地做到这一点，即使我们要编写，我们也必须编写OpenGL代码
because we'll be able to do that rather easily, even if we do like we will have to write, we will have to write OpenGL code
基本上我是这么说的，因为我们还没有渲染器，所以我分心了
basically what I'm saying, because we don't have a renderer yet, so I'm distracted
但一旦我们有了渲染器，一旦它被抽象了
but once we do have a Renderer, once that easy abstracted
将能够转换ImGui层和ImGui渲染器的代码
will be able to convert that ImGui layer and that ImGui code that ImGui renderer
基本上是使用Hazel的接口，那将非常棒，因为它意味着
essentially to use Hazel's api, and that'll be awesome, because it'll mean
首先，我们将有一种，我将为所有渲染接口提供渲染实现
first of all, we'll have one kind of, I'm going rendering implementation for all rendering apis
就像我们有了DirectX和所有东西一样
like once we have DirectX and everything
会很好的，但也会很好
it'll just be just be great, but also, uh also it will be um, it'll kind of well in general just
它将只使用Hazel，因此只使用原始OpenGL调用，这是我们无论如何都不想做的
it'll just use Hazel, and so just using raw OpenGL calls, which we which we don't want to do anyway
所以那将是下一期的计划，应该是快速而杂乱的，但我确实想放进去
so that's gonna be the plan for the next episode, should be kind of quick and dirty, but I do want to get it in
因为当我们构建渲染器时，能够有一个UI，这将非常重要，那就是为什么我想先做这件事
because when we are building our renderer, being able to have a UI, it's gonna be really important, that's why I kind of want to do this first
希望你们喜欢这期视频，下次见，拜
ho hope you guys enjoyed this video, I'll see you in the next one, goodbye